JONAH BELMAN

Canadian student w/ ability to work in the US

Email

jbelman@uwaterloo.ca

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/jonahbel

Portfolio

www.jonahbelman.me

I am an engineering student with a strong interest and experience in robotics and the automotive industry. I love working with my hands and creating things. I am a hard worker and can quickly learn new skills when put to the task.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Adept at 2D & 3D design with SolidWorks and AutoCad using GD&T
- Well-versed in product design and prototyping with Arduino, Raspberry Pi, and 3D printing
- Highly experienced in circuit/PCB design and soldering
- Proficient in Java, C++, C, SQL, MATLAB, HTML, and CSS
- Hands-on experience with woodworking and machining

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Captain and Powertrain Lead / UW Baja SAE Team, Waterloo, ON

01/2021 - Present

- Leading design and construction of the powertrain for a Baja off-roading vehicle, set to compete in 2022
- Researched, designed, and machined components for transmission, transfer case, and differentials for the first ever 4WD/AWD Baja SAE competition
- Elected Team Captain, therefore responsible for managing 4 sub-teams and overseeing team operation
- Accumulated upwards of \$20,000 in funds through sponsor outreach and communication

Electrical Hardware Designer / Genesis 3 Engineering, Kitchener, ON

05/2021 - 08/2021

- Performed electrical safety reviews of industrial equipment using Sistema to ensure safety standards were upheld
- Designed wiring diagrams of industrial machinery using Eplan while maintaining proper electrical engineering practices
- Modified over 2500 safety circuits and related schematics to comply with safety standards, such as ISO 13849

Robotics Engineering Co-op / Top Hat Robotics, Kitchener, ON

09/2020 - 12/2020

- Modelled, assembled, and tested semi-autonomous sidewalk robots used for snow and ice removal
- Redesigned battery storage department leading to a 300% increase in robot's battery life
- Managed electrical components and power distribution in several robots
- Soldered and wired components to custom PCBs

Owner and Design Lead / Toronto Custom Woodworking, Toronto, ON

05/2019 - 12/2020

- Planned and developed start-up company building breathtaking tables and a bar out of recycled materials
- Designed and constructed one-of-a-kind modern furniture pieces for clients
- Communicated with clients to fully understand their custom orders and provide project timeline updates
- Managed social media account (@tocustomwoodworking on Instagram) to reach out to future clients

Engineering Co-op / ORION, Toronto, ON

01/2020 - 05/2020

- Organized and installed fiber-optic servers and switches into province-wide server rooms
- Managed company assets and inventory, saving the engineering team 3 hours/week, on average
- Programmed several automation processes on Customer Relation Management (CRM) software

PERSONAL PROJECTS AND AWARDS

Electric Jet Boat 07/2021 – Present

- Designed a fully electric sport boat to provide sustainable alternative to gas-powered watercrafts
- Modelled vehicle and jet drive propulsion on SolidWorks and other CAD software
- Composed electrical schematics and safety calculations on EPLAN and Sistema respectively

1st Place – Weizmann International Physics Competition

09/2018 - 04/2019

- Designed and constructed a "safe" with locking mechanisms based on principles of physics
- Programmed and wired electronic components of the safe
- Awarded 1st place in worldwide competition of 144 teams

EDUCATION